Guide to the Bristol Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Bristol family papers
1769-1877
MS 101
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
16.75
Correspondence, financial records, diaries, scrapbooks, account books and memorabilia of the Bristol family of New Haven and New London, Connecticut. The major figures in the collection are the descendants of Simeon Bristol (1739-1805); his son, William Bristol, and his grandsons, William Brooks Bristol, and Louis Bristol, all prominent lawyers, judges and members of the state legislature in Connecticut.Nearly a third of the papers is made up of land deeds for New Haven and New London counties (1765-1854). The voluminous correspondence (2,569 letters) extends over several generations from 1798 to 1879. Of particular interest are the fifty-one letters by Louis Bristol written from Paris to family members and to Timothy Dwight Edwards describing the Revolution of 1830. Between 1829 and 1857 William Brooks Bristol wrote 581 letters to his brother Louis, chiefly on the question of buying and selling railroad stocks. Additional papers of the brothers include records of their law practice, account books and business corrspondence. Also a diary (1834-1844) kept by Louis Bristol recording his life as a student at Yale College, his surveying experience and his courtship, together with twenty-nine compositions written while at Yale. Eugene Stuart Bristol, son of William Brooks Bristol, is represented by letter books and extensive financial records (1869-1873) documenting his mining operations at Bingham Canyon, Utah.
Bristol family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were purchased from Messrs. Todd, Whitlock, and Means and a portion were given by Maria T. Dana, ca. 1945.
Biographical / Historical
LOUIS BRISTOL, 1814-1882
LOUIS BRISTOL, son of Judge William Bristol (Y. C. 1798) and Sarah (Edwards) Bristol, was born in New Haven, Conn., December 18, 1814. He entered College in 1830, but left during the Freshman year, to resume his studies a year later.
He was occupied for five years after graduation as a civil engineer in the surveys for new railroads in Connecticut, New York, and Illinois. He then studied law in the Yale Law School, was admitted to the bar in 1843, and settled in New Haven. He married, May 29, 1844, Mary D., only daughter of William P. Cleaveland, Jr., (Y. C. 1816), of New London, Conn., by whom he had three sons and one daughter. In 1857 the failure of his health led him to give up his professional practice, and in 1859 he removed to Makanda, a small town in Southern Illinois, where he undertook farming and fruit raising thus securing the reestablishment of his health. In February, 1865, his wife obtained a divorce, and in January, 1866, he married Augusta, the daughter of Col. Otis Cooper, of Croydon, N. H., and formerly the wife of Gustavus F. Kimball, of East Canaan, N. H. They resided at first in Carbondale, Ill., and in 1872 removed to a farm in Vineland, N. J., where he died December 21, 1882, at the age of 68.
(Taken from the Yale Obituary Record )
WILLIAM BROOKS BRISTOL, 1806-1876
WILLIAM BROOKS BRISTOL, son of Wm. Bristol (of the class of 1798) and Sarah Edwards, and the grandson of Simeon Bristol (of the class of 1760), was born in New Haven, Conn., June, 1806, and died in that city after a long illness, October 10, 1876.
Upon his graduation, Mr. Bristol entered upon the study of law at the Law School in New Haven, and in the office of his father, Judge Bristol, and on the completion of his legal studies practiced law for one or two years in Painesville, Ohio. He then returned to his native place and resumed practice there, and continued it successfully with the general public esteem and the fullest confidence of those with whom he had relations of business in his integrity, judgment, and ability, nearly to the close of his life.
Mr. Bristol was twice married: first to Mary Bliss, of Springfield, Mass., Nov. 15, 1836, who died Feb. 15, 1849, by whom he had six children, of whom two sons survive him (both graduates of this college), and secondly, Nov. 11, 1850, to Caroline Bliss, of the same place, by whom he has had three children (one of them a member of the graduating class of this year), who with their mother are still living.
(Taken from the Yale Obituary Record .)
WILLIAM BRISTOL, 1779-1836
WILLIAM BRISTOL, the youngest son of Judge Simeon Bristol (Yale 1760), of Hamden, then part of New Haven, was born on June 2, 1779.
He studied law in the office of the Hon. David Daggett, and was admitted to the bar in New Haven County in November, 1800. In 1800-1802 his father built for him the handsome house on Elm Street, after the pattern of the adjacent mansion of Judge Daggett, which was torn down in 1908 to make room for the new Public Library.
He was Speaker of the House of Representatives of Connecticut in 1817. He represented New Haven in the Convention held in Hartford in 1818 which formed the present State constitution.
In 1818 and 1819 he was a member of the State Senate, and ( ex-officio) of the Corporation of the College.
In 1819, at the comparatively early age of forty, he was appointed Judge of the Superior Court and Supreme Court of Errors, which office he held until his resignation in 1826, having in that year been appointed Judge of the District Court of the United States for the District of Connecticut, in which latter office he continued until his death.
He was elected an alderman of the city in 1818, 1821, and 1826, and Mayor in June, 1827, holding the office for one year. In 1825 he was nominated by his political friends as candidate for Governor, but declined, preferring the quietude of the judicial station to the excitements attending a political canvass.
In 1830 he was joined with Judge Samuel Church (Yale 1803) in the report of a new and revised criminal code for the State.
He died suddenly, after a period of infirmity, in New Haven, on Monday evening, March 7, 1836, in his 57th year.
Judge Bristol was a man of superior mental powers, which he cultivated with untiring industry. His learning, ability, and integrity, united with a courteous urbanity, elicited the admiration of his professional brethren and won the confidence of the community. "As a judge he was the favorite of everyone, judges, jurors, witnesses, and counsel, all bore willing testimony to the ability and impartiality with which his official duty was invariably performed. Towards the younger members of the profession he was particularly kind, attentive, and encouraging; and no young man practicing before him could feel the slightest apprehension that the merits of his case would be overlooked in the decision, no matter how diffident he might be in presenting his views, or however powerful and experienced might be the counsel opposed to him. Such was the confidence placed in the decisions of Judge Bristol, that controversies involving large sums and intricate questions, were frequently referred to him by the parties, and were quietly disposed of in a short time in his office, which would otherwise have required months or years of expensive litigation." He lived universally respected, and his death was deeply lamented.
He was married, in New Haven, on January 6, 1805, by the Rev. Dr. Bela Hubbard, to Sarah (or Sally) Edwards, of New Haven, who died on December 24, 1866, aged 86 years. Three sons were graduates of Yale, in 1825, 1827, and 1835, and a daughter married John Murdoch (Yale 1834).
His only separate publication, over his own name, was the following:
An Address, intended to have been delivered (in substance) at the late Town Meeting, in New-Haven; in Reply to the reasons urged for requesting His Excellency the Governor to convene the General Assembly, to take into consideration the alarming situation of Public Affairs; but prevented from being delivered by causes herein explained. Together with a Short Account of that Extraordinary Meeting, by William Bristoll, Esq. New-Haven, 1809. 8°, pp. 19. [ M. H. S. N. Y. H. S. Y. C. ]
In defence of the Embargo. The Address seems to have been hooted down by the opposition.
He delivered the Fourth of July Oration in New Haven in 1800, but it does not seem to have been printed.
Authorities: Kilbourn, Litchfield County Bench and Bar, 77. N.H. City Year Book, 1863. 97-98. N.H. Daily Herald, March 8 and 9, 1836. Storer's Amer. Hist. Magazine, 158.
(Taken from Annals of Yale Men by F.B. Dexter, vol. 4)
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, financial records, diaries, scrapbooks, account books and memorabilia of the Bristol family of New Haven and New London, Connecticut. The major figures in the collection are the descendants of Simeon Bristol (1739-1805); his son, William Bristol, and his grandsons, William Brooks Bristol, and Louis Bristol, all prominent lawyers, judges and members of the state legislature in Connecticut.Nearly a third of the papers is made up of land deeds for New Haven and New London counties (1765-1854). The voluminous correspondence (2,569 letters) extends over several generations from 1798 to 1879. Of particular interest are the fifty-one letters by Louis Bristol written from Paris to family members and to Timothy Dwight Edwards describing the Revolution of 1830. Between 1829 and 1857 William Brooks Bristol wrote 581 letters to his brother Louis, chiefly on the question of buying and selling railroad stocks. Additional papers of the brothers include records of their law practice, account books and business corrspondence. Also a diary (1834-1844) kept by Louis Bristol recording his life as a student at Yale College, his surveying experience and his courtship, together with twenty-nine compositions written while at Yale. Eugene Stuart Bristol, son of William Brooks Bristol, is represented by letter books and extensive financial records (1869-1873) documenting his mining operations at Bingham Canyon, Utah.
Arrangement
Arranged in nine series: I. William Bristol Papers, 1799-1867, II. Louis Bristol Papers, 1843-1857, III. William Brooks Bristol Papers, 1828-1859, IV. Eugene Stuart Bristol Papers, 1868-1879, V. Legal Files, 1803-1872, VI. Miscellaneous Papers, 1767-1874, VII. Family Papers, 1789-1929, VIII. Personal Papers, 1774-1865, and IX. Financial Records.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Banks and banking; Business; Courtship; Families; Law; Mines and mineral resources -- Utah; Railroads -- Finance; Travelers -- Europe; Women -- Education; Connecticut; Europe; France -- Description and travel; France -- History -- July Revolution, 1830; Great Britain -- Description and travel; Guildhall (Vt.); Italy -- Description and travel; Marcellus (N.Y.); New Haven (Conn.); New London (Conn.); West (U.S.); Account books; Deeds; Diaries; Scrapbooks; Lawyers; Legislators; Beers, Seth P. (Seth Preston), 1781-1862; Bliss, William, 1806-1886; Bristol, Albert Gallatin, 1808-1873; Bristol, Caroline Bliss, 1817-; Bristol, Eugene Stuart, 1843-1910; Bristol, John Wolcott, 1855-1922; Bristol, Louis Henry, 1839-1910; Bristol, Louis, 1814-1882; Bristol, Mary Dwight Cleaveland; Bristol, Mary Wolcott Bliss, 1810-1849; Bristol, Sarah Edwards, 1780-1866; Bristol, Simeon, 1739-1805; Bristol, Simeon, 1764-; Bristol, William Brooks, 1806-1876; Bristol, William, 1847-1873; Chaplain, Anne Francis Murdoch; Chapman, Simeon B.; Clap, William, 1779-1860; Cleaveland, Mary Sanford Dwight, 1797-1854; Cleaveland, William B., 1828-; Cleaveland, William Pitt, 1770-1845; Dana, Caroline Louise Bristol, 1857-1916; Draper, Minnie L.; Edwards, Alfred P.; Whitney, Henrietta Edwards, 1785-1870; Edwards, Henry Waggaman, 1770-1847; Edwards, Ogden, 1781-1862; Edwards, Pierpont, 1750-1826; Fisher, George Park, 1827-1909; Harris, Jedediah H.; Hosmer, S. Titus (Stephen Titus), 1763-1834; Jones, Eliza Perkins Sparhawk, -1882; Law, Jonathan, 1784-1859; Mansfield, Emily D.; Murdoch, Frances Louisa Bristol, -1875; Murdoch, Jane; Murdoch, John, 1813-1861; Paine, Sarah May, 1821-1908; Peters, John Thompson, 1765-1834; Sherman, Roger M. (Roger Minott), 1773-1844; Skinner, A. N. (Aaron Nichols), 1800-1858; Stewart, James, 1775-1821; Stoddard, Maria Teresa; Trask, Eliza L.; Van Santvoord, Katharine L.; Van Santvoord, Zaidee; Whittemore, Samuel, 1694-1793; Bliss family; Bristol family; Cleveland family; Cedar Grove Cemetery (New London, Conn.); Miss Porter's School (Farmington, Conn.); National Whaling Bank (New London, Conn.); Vermont. Department of Taxes; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1835; Yale University -- Students
- WILLIAM BRISTOL PAPERS, 1799-1867; Series I
  - General
    - A - W (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Select
    - Alken, J., 1799 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Allen, Frederick, 1815-1818 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Arms, Pliney, 1814 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Barker, G.C., 1825-1826 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Barnes, Jonathan, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Beach, David, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Beers, Seth Preston, 1812-1823 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bixby, John, 1821-1824 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Brainard, Jeremiah Gates, 1824 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bray, A., 1812-1815 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bristol, Louis, 1829-1845 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bristol, Simeon, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bristol, William B., undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Brooks, Miah, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Catlin, Lynde, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Chapman, Asa, 1820-1824 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Chapman, Simeon B., 1816-1822 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Church, Samuel, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Clap, William, 1809-1811 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Cleaveland, William Pitt, 1813-1815 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Daggett, David, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Danis, Ezra, 1809-1812 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Day, Thomas, 1818-1827 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - DeForest, Benjamin, 1824-1828 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - DeForest, John Hancock, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Dunham, David, 1813 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Edwards, Alfred P., 1816-1817 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Edwards, Henry W., 1820-1833 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Edwards, Ogdin, 1811-1828 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Edwards, Pierrepont, 1800-1823 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Hall, Jonathan P., 1825 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Harrison, J., 1812-1816 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Hawley, William, 1816-1817 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Holmes, Reuben, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Huntington, Jake, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Isaacs, Benjamin, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Ives, Nathaniel, 1817 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Ives, Oliver, 1816-1817 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Jones, Joel, 1823-1824 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Judson, Agar, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Judson, Andrew, 1824-1825 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Law, Jonathan, 1808-1816 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Learned, Elizabeth, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Malcolm, Donald, 1816-1817 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Manwaring, C., 1818 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Mills, Isaac, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Mitchell, Aaron, 1815-1817 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Olmsted, Elihu, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Palmer, Joseph, 1815-1816 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Perkins, Elias, 1823 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Peters, John T., 1816-1825 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Phelps, Elisha, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Pond, Charles H., 1823 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Porter, E.A., 1867 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Pitman, John, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Preston, Nathan, 1814-1817 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Rankin, Christopher, 1823 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Rogers, Benjamin W., 1813 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Rossoter, William Sidney, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Shepherd, Charles, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Sherman, Roger M., 1824 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Smith, Richard, 1830-1834 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Stanley, George Washington, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Staples, Seth Perkins, 1799-1883 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Starrs, William Lucius, 1830 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Stewart, James, 1812-1818 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Stoutenburgh, John, 1812-1813 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Strong, Henry, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Thompson, James, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Tillotson, Daniel, 1799 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Tracy, Elisha, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Van Deurson, William, 1817 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Waters, Isaac, 1812-1813 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Whiting, Samuel, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Whitman, Lemeul, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Whittemore, Samuel, 1812-1815 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Whittlesey, Roger, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Willey, Calvin, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Williams, Joseph, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Williams, Thomas Scott, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Miscellanea, 1799-1828 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Financial records
    - Bank book, 1826-1830 (Box 2, Folder 85)
- LOUIS BRISTOL PAPERS, 1843-1857; Series II
  - General
    - A - Z (Box 3, Folder 86-93)
  - Select (Incoming)
    - Ainsworth, Calvin, 1849-1852 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Allyn, Samuel D., 1854-1855 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Bacon, Asa, 1846 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Barney, Edwin L., 1854-1855 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Baxter, B., 1851-1857 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Benedict, Hall and Co., 1854 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Brawn, Stephen and Sons, 1848-1850 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Bliss, William, 1852-1855 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Bristol, Albert G., 1843 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Bristol, Sarah, 1843 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Bristol, William Brooks, 1843-1854 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Burritt, Ransom, 1850-1851 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Chappell, James L., 1849 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Clark, Gerardus, 1853-1854 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Cleaveland, Ira, 1844-1845 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Coit, Robert, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Cox, Christopher Christian, 1835 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Darrow, S., 1854-1855 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Davis, Abner, 1848-1855 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Davis, John, 1835-1837 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Day, Benjamin, 1844-1857 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Dennett, James S., 1855-1857 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Dewey, Egbert, 1839-1845 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Dwight, Aurelia, undated (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Dwight, George, 1846-1857 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Fentone, Joseph Brush, 1835-1837 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Finn, John R., 1848 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Fletcher, Arthur, 1848-1850 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Ford, George H., 1853-1855 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Foster, L., 1846-1857 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Fuller, John P., 1851 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Calpin, P., 1845-1846 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Gilbert, Charles J., 1855-1858 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Gilbert, George W., 1857 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Goddard, James E., 1858 (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Harris, I., 1856-1857 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Holmes, Booth and Hayden, 1855-1856 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Hotchkiss, H., 1850-1857 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - Hotchkiss, H. and L., 1850-1851 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Hull, William B., 1853 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Kidden, N., 1847-1850 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Kimberly, Dennis, 1843 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Lackawanna Iron and Coal Co., 1858 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Lehmer, James, 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Loomis, Osbert, 1835-1836 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Lyman, H., 1856 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - McAllister, Robert, 1857-1858 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - McEwen, W.B., 1850 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - McLoughlin, M., 1853 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Millbank, I., 1857 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Murdoch, Frances Louise, undated (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Murdoch, John, 1843 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Nagle, I., 1852-1853 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Nevins, D.H., 1854 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Olcott, John J., 1854-1855 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - O'Reilly, Henry, 1852-1853 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Rogers, P., 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Seeley, Ebenezer, 1845-1856 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Seeley, Uri, 1848-1849 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Shelton and Flagg, 1844-1848 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Shipman and Ayres, 1845-1848 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Shipman, W., 1853-1854 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Sill and Kidder, 1844-1846 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Smith, R., 1852 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Stevens, Edwards and Meade, 1852 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Sturges, Theo, 1855-1857 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Van Schaal, Olcott and Reynolds, 1847 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Vermilge, W., 1845 (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - Walker, Frederick, 1845-1852 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Ward and Co., 1850-1857 (Box 5, Folder 163-165)
    - Welch, J., 1849 (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Welles, W., 1853 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Whitney and Ferns, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Williams, Henry, 1843 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Winslow, Lanier and Co., 1853 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - Witt, John D., 1843 (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - General (Outgoing)
    - A - Z (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - Select (Outgoing)
    - Bristol, Albert G., 1857 (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Bristol, Eugene Stuart, 1870-1872 (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - Bristol, Louis Henry, 1857 (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - Bristol, Mary D., 1857 (Box 5, Folder 176)
    - Bristol, William B., 1844-1857 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Cleaveland, William B., 1847-1857 (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - Dwight, George, 1845-1855 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Goddard, George W., 1848-1856 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Goddard, George W., 1849 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Murdoch, John, 1842 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Paine, Sarah, 1856-1857 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Sanford, Mary, 1844-1854 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - Walker, Frederick M., 1845-1846 (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - Topical Files
    - Account books, 1849, 1853-1858 (Box 5, Folder 186-187)
    - Agreement, 1849 (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - Appointment as rotary public, 1845 (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - Cashbook, 1845-1846 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Journal, 1834-1844 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Journal, 1854 January - April (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Letterbook, 1851-1853 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Superior Court docket, 1843-1845 (Box 6, Folder 194)
- WILLIAM BROOKS BRISTOL PAPERS, 1828-1859; Series III
  - Correspondence
    - A - Z (Box 7, Folder 195)
    - Bond, Thomas H., 1828 (Box 7, Folder 196)
    - Bristol, Eugene, 1871 (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - Bristol, Louis, 1846-1855 April (Box 7, Folder 198-213)
    - Bristol, Louis, 1855 May - 1857 (Box 8, Folder 214-216)
    - Bristol, Mary, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Bristol, Sarah, 1848-1859 (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - Daggett, Ellsworth, 1871 (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - Murdock, Frances Louise, undated (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - Shipman and Ayres, 1846 (Box 8, Folder 221)
  - Scrapbook, undated (Box 8, Folder 222)
- EUGENE STUART BRISTOL PAPERS, 1868-1879; Series IV
  - Correspondence
    - Bliss, Emily C., undated (Box 9, Folder 223)
    - Bristol, John W., 1872 (Box 9, Folder 224)
    - Bristol, Mary B., 1868-1879 (Box 9, Folder 225)
    - Bristol. Mary B. and Caroline L., 1873 (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - Bristol, William B., 1871 (Box 9, Folder 227)
    - Dana, Caroline Louise, 1879 (Box 9, Folder 228)
    - Miscellanea, 1871, undated (Box 9, Folder 229)
  - Financial papers
    - Account books
      - General, 1870 (Box 9, Folder 230)
      - Bullion shipping, 1871-1872 (Box 9, Folder 231)
      - Charcoal, 1870-1871 (Box 9, Folder 232)
      - Mine materials, 1871-1872 (Box 9, Folder 233-234)
    - Bank books, 1870-1871 (Box 10, Folder 235-236)
    - Furnace book, 1870-1871 (Box 10, Folder 237)
    - Oversize material, 1870-1872 Jun, undated (Box 43–44)
  - Miscellanea
    - Letterbooks, 1870-1873 (Box 10, Folder 238-239)
    - Notebooks, 1868, undated (Box 10, Folder 240-241)
    - Timebooks, 1871-1872 (Box 10, Folder 242-243)
- LEGAL FILES, 1803-1872; Series V
  - Bristol and Goddard
    - A - Z (Box 11, Folder 244-250)
  - Daggett and Bristol
    - A - Z, 1871-1872 (Box 11, Folder 251-253)
    - Allen, J.M. and Co., 1871-1872 (Box 11, Folder 254)
    - Bank of Deserot, 1871-1872 (Box 11, Folder 255)
    - Bulkly and Brother, 1852 (Box 11, Folder 256)